Jeremy Clough

Newbury, RG14 clough.jeremy@gmail.com

Degree educated Engineer with a background in providing advanced software technical support to Enterprise customers. I have experience of investigating complex software issues to code level in both UNIX/Linux and Windows environments. With a background that has included working as a Release Engineer, a Software Developer and a Support Engineer, I have experience of the full software lifecycle and how to communicate software issues to Project Managers, Engineering teams, Support teams and customers. With an attention to detail and a focus on doing things the right way, I enjoy utilizing my software coding skills and experience to get to the root of a problem.

Employment

Symantec/Veritas, Reading, RG2 6UH

Advanced Support Engineer for Symantec/Veritas eDiscovery Platform

March 2012 - today

Provide support to Enterprise customers using the Veritas Clearwell eDiscovery software product. Clearwell supports the full EDRM eDiscovery workflow and is based around a Tomcat webserver running on a Windows Server. Various plugin software components, written in a variety of software languages, provide the ability to collect file and email data from numerous different sources. My work involves investigating product issues to code-level (primarily C/C++ and Java), debugging using windbg and Eclipse and reproducing issues for escalation to our Engineering team. This upfront analysis work is also used for the creation of technical knowledgebase articles for internal and customer use, and for constructing software patches that can give the Engineering team a starting-off point for the issue.

Barracuda Networks, Basingstoke, RG22 6HY

Barracuda Networks manufactures and provides 24/7 support for network appliances based on the Linux OS and Open Source technologies including Apache, MySQL, Postfix, and Perl.

Technical Support Engineer

Feb 2010 - Feb 2012

Provided telephone and email support to EMEA customers. Remotely accessed the command-line and web UI of customer devices to troubleshoot product software and hardware issues. Logged bug reports for new issues, with reproduction steps, and, when possible, investigated problems to source code level (mainly Perl), identifying software fixes or workarounds for the customer. Support was provided for the following products: Barracuda Email anti-spam appliance, Barracuda Backup appliance.

Micro Focus Ltd, Newbury, RG14 1QN

The major Micro Focus product is a COBOL software development environment for Windows and UNIX/Linux platforms. The product enables companies to migrate their legacy COBOL-based software systems to modern platforms and extend them with technologies such as Web Services, J2EE, .Net and XML.

Software Developer

January 2009 - Aug 2009

Following agile software development practices (Scrum), as a member of the 'Core' development team, investigated and resolved problems with the COBOL debug engine and COBOL runtime system (both written in C). Added and maintained accompanying automated tests.

Senior Software Release Engineer

April 2003 - December 2008

As a senior member of the Release Engineering team, produced the software builds and Fix-packs for the Micro Focus Server Express product. Platforms supported included IBM AIX, Compaq Tru64, HP-UX (PA-RISC, Itanium), Red Hat (x86-64, PPC, 390), Solaris (Intel, Sparc), SuSE (x86-64, PPC, 390) and SCO UnixWare. Working very closely with Project Management, Development, Testing and Support, integrated new software components into the build system and ensured availability of daily product builds. Investigated build issues (make/imake/Ant), and runtime and test system issues. Helped maintain the in-house custom automated product build, installation and Fix-pack systems. Produced initial ports of the product to new UNIX and Linux platforms.

Compaq Computer Ltd, Reading, RG2 OTE

Systems Development/Integration Engineer, UK Telecommunications Integration Service (TIS) practice.

June 1999 - Aug 2002

Created and maintained software components for major Telecomms companies including Vodafone, BT, Alcatel and Cable & Wireless. These components were created to plug into the Compaq TeMIP© Network Management software framework. Investigated legacy software issues. Implemented and documented new functionality.

Kerridge Computer Company Ltd, Newbury, RG14 1HT

Kerridge Computer Company were an independent software house, providing software solutions for Distribution, Wholesale and Merchant industries.

UNIX Software Engineer

Sept 1996 - Sept 1997

Programmed in C on UNIX using the Lex and Yacc tools, to extend the features of the in-house interpreted programming language called KCML (Kerridge C Macro Language).

Education

1992 – 1996 Master of Engineering (MEng) 2:1 Hons

Mechanical Engineering with German University of Birmingham, Edgbaston, B15 2TT

1990 - 1992 **A-Level**

Little Heath Secondary School, Tilehurst, Reading, Berks Pure Maths (A), Applied Maths (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (C)